我知道你在想什么
Now, I know what you're thinking.
不  托尔被关在笼子里了  怎么回事
"Oh, no! Thor's in a cage. How did this happen?"
有时  你得先被抓住
Well, sometimes you have to get captured
才能从某人那里问出个所以然来
just to get a straight answer out of somebody.
说来话长  但其实  我算是个英雄
It's a long story, but basically, I'm a bit of a hero.
我去地球待了一阵
See, I spent some time on Earth...
打过几个机器人  救了地球几次
Fought some robots, saved the planet a couple of times.
然后我去宇宙中寻找
Then I went searching through the cosmos
几颗有魔法的多彩的无限宝石
for some magic, colorful Infinity Stone things.
但没找到
Didn't find any.
这时我遇到了一条死亡和毁灭之路
That's when I came across a path of death and destruction,
而因此来到了这个笼子里
which led me all the way here into this cage,
还遇见了你
where I met you.
你觉得我们还要在这里待多久
How much longer do you think we'll be here?
托尔  奥丁之子
Thor, son of Odin.
苏尔特尔  王八之子
Surtur, son of a bitch.
你还活着
You're still alive.
我以为我父亲50万年前杀掉你了
I thought my father killed you like, a half a million years ago.
我不能死
I cannot die.
我还没有实现命运
Not until I fulfill my destiny
毁灭你的家乡
and lay waste to your home.
正好你提起这个了
You know, it's funny you should mention that.
因为我最近一直在做噩梦
Because I've been having these terrible dreams of late.
阿斯加德陷入烈火  成为一片灰烬
Asgard up in flames, falling to ruins.
而你  苏尔特尔  处于那一切之中
And you, Surtur, are at the center of all of them.
那你已经见识到了诸神黄昏  阿斯加德的陨落
Then you have seen Ragnarok, the fall of Asgard.
-伟大的预言  -等等
- The great prophecy... - Hang on.
等等
Hang on.
我马上就能转回去
I'll be back around shortly.
我真觉得我们刚刚聊得很投机
I really feel like we were connecting there.
好了  诸神黄昏  跟我讲讲  仔细说说
Okay, so Ragnarok. Tell me about that. Walk me through it.
我的时代到来了
My time has come.
等我的王冠再次沐浴永恒烈火
When my crown is reunited with the Eternal Flame,
我就将恢复全部力量
I shall be restored to my full might.
比山还高
I will tower over the mountains,
把剑深深插入阿斯加德的...
and bury my sword deep in Asgard's...
等等  等一下
Hang on. Give it a second.
我发誓  我根本没动  是它自己在转
I swear, I'm not even moving. It's just doing this on its own.
真的很抱歉
I'm really sorry.
好了  是这么回事吗
Okay, so let me get this straight.
你要把你的王冠放进永恒烈火里
You're going to put your crown into the Eternal Flame
然后你会突然变得有房子那么大
and then you'll suddenly grow as big as a house?
是山
A mountain!
永恒烈火是奥丁锁在阿斯加德的那个
The Eternal Flame that Odin keeps locked away on Asgard?
奥丁不在阿斯加德
Odin is not on Asgard.
而你的离开让王权失去了防卫
And your absence has left the throne defenseless.
好吧  那王冠在哪呢
Okay, so where is it? This crown?
这就是我的王冠  我力量的源泉
This is my crown, the source of my power.
那是王冠啊  我以为你是眉毛长得比较夸张
Oh, that's a crown. I thought it was a big eyebrow.
是王冠
It's a crown.
总之  听上去  我想阻止诸神黄昏
Anyway, it sounds like all I have to do to stop Ragnarok
只需要扯下你脑袋上那玩意
is rip that thing off your head.
但诸神黄昏已经开始了
But Ragnarok has already begun.
你无法阻止
You cannot stop it.
我是阿斯加德的末日  你也是
I am Asgard's doom, and so are you.
一切都将遭受煎熬  被烈火吞噬
All will suffer, all will burn.
好紧张
That's intense.
老实说  看着你变得老大
To be honest, seeing you grow really big
然后烧掉一颗星球  肯定很壮观
and set fire to a planet would be quite the spectacle.
但看来我只能选择第二条路
But it looks like I'm gonna have to choose option B,
那就是我挣脱这铁链
where I bust out of these chains,
把你的头饰从脑袋上砸下来
knock that tiara off your head,
然后藏在阿斯加德的地堡里
and stash it away in Asgard's vault.
你无法阻止诸神黄昏
You cannot stop Ragnarok.
何必抵抗呢
Why fight it?
因为  英雄都会这么做
Because that's what heroes do.
等等  抱歉  我时机掐得不太好
Wait, I'm sorry. I didn't time that right.
来了
And, now!
BGM: Immigrant Song  By  Led Zeppelin
你犯了个大错误  奥丁森
You have made a grave mistake, Odinson.
我经常犯大错误
I make grave mistakes all the time.
看来结果还不错嘛
Everything seems to work out.
海姆达尔  我知道我们好久没联系了
Heimdall, I know it's been a while,
但我真的很需要赶紧离开这里
but I could really use a fast exit.
海姆达尔
Heimdall?
海姆达尔就是个蠢货
Heimdall was an idiot.
这份工作本该让他发财的
This job should have made him rich.
这份工作并不轻松
Now, the job ain't easy
但还是有些好处的
but it does have its benefits.
彩虹桥让我可以接触到
The Bifrost gives me access
九大王国的一切
to everything the Nine Realms has to offer.
我想拿就拿
I mean, it's all mine for the taking.
看啊
Behold...
我的东西
My stuff.
我特别喜欢这俩玩意
I'm particularly fond of these.
我从米德加德一个叫德克萨斯的地方拿到了它们
I pulled them out of a place on Midgard called Texas.
我还给它们起了名字  毁天和灭地
I even named them. Des and Troy.
因为  当它们合在一起
You see, when you put them together,
就能毁天灭地
they destroy.
海姆达尔  拜托了
Heimdall, come on.
别动
Stay!
海姆达尔  我要没招了
Heimdall? I'm running short on options.
海姆达尔
Heimdall?
斯科尔奇
Skurge?
那个要紧吗
Is that important?
你们俩姑娘今天有好戏看了
You girls are in for a treat.
雷神3：诸神黄昏
姑娘们
Girls!
哎呦呦
Well, well, well.
看看是谁决定回来了
Look who decided to pop in.
感谢你吓跑了我的女伴
Thanks for scaring away my company
还弄得我的办公场所全是脑浆
and drenching my workplace in brains.
你是谁
Who are you?
你不记得了吗  斯科尔奇
Don't you remember? I'm Skurge.
我们曾在华纳海姆并肩作战
We fought together on Vanaheim.
想起来了
Right.
海姆达尔呢
Where is Heimdall?
那个叛徒  没人知道  他是王室逃犯
That traitor. Well, no one knows. He's a fugitive of the throne.
叛徒
Traitor?
对  奥丁指控海姆达尔玩忽职守
Yeah. You see, Odin charged Heimdall with negligence of duty
但他在审判前就消失不见了
but he disappeared before the trial.
想抓住一个能洞察宇宙中一切的人可不容易
Hard to catch a guy who can see everything in the universe.
-是啊  -等等
- Sure. - Hold on. Hold on.
我要宣告你的到来的
I'm supposed to announce your arrival.
这是什么玩意
What the hell is that?
哥哥  时候到了
Oh, brother. This is it.
我要离世了
I take my leave.
你真傻  怎么不听我的
You fool, you didn't listen!
对不起
I'm sorry.
希芙女士  去找人帮忙
Lady Sif, get help!
谁来帮帮忙啊
Somebody, help!
我为我做的一切道歉
I'm sorry for all I've done.
没事的  撑住
It's all right. Hold on.
抱歉我企图统治地球
I'm sorry I tried to rule Earth.
有你只会是他们的幸运
They'd be lucky to have you.
宇宙魔方的事我也很抱歉
I'm sorry about that thing with the Tesseract.
-我就是忍不住  -我知道
- I just couldn't help myself. - I know.
-我喜欢耍诡计  -是啊
- I'm a trickster. - Yes.
总爱搞恶作剧
So mischievous.
抱歉我那次把你变成了只青蛙
Sorry about that time I turned you into a frog.
那是很有趣的笑话
It was a wonderful joke.
的确是非常好笑
'Twas indeed hilarious.
你是阿斯加德的拯救者
You are the savior of Asgard.
-讲述我的故事  -我会的
- Tell my story. - I will.
为我建一座雕像
Build a statue for me.
我们会为你建一座大雕像的
We will build a big statue for you.
还要戴着我的头盔  有大弯角的那个
With my helmet on, with the big bendy horns.
你的英勇我会禀告父王
I will tell Father what you did here today.
我不是为了他
I didn't do it for him.
不
No!
洛基因伤不治而死
And so, Loki died of his wounds,
他为我们献出了生命
giving his life for ours.
他击退了那些可憎的精灵
He fought back those disgusting elves,
为王国带来了和平
he brought peace to the realm.
洛基  我的儿子
Loki, my boy...
多年前  我在那覆满冰霜的战场上发现了你
'Twas many moons ago I found you on that frostbitten battlefield.
那天  我尚未看出你是
On that day, I did not yet see in you
阿斯加德的拯救者  是啊
Asgard's savior. No.
你只是个小蓝冰棍
You were merely a little blue baby icicle
却融化了我这老傻瓜的心
that melted this old fool's heart.
精彩  精彩  演得好
Bravo! Bravo! Well done. Bravo.
父亲
Father.
该死
Shit.
我的儿子  托尔回来了
My son, Thor, has returned!
你好  我的孩子
Greetings, my boy.
这出戏真有趣  叫什么
It's an interesting play. What's it called?
《阿斯加德的洛基之惨剧》
The Tragedy of Loki of Asgard.
人民想纪念他
The people wanted to commemorate him.
他们是该如此
Indeed they should.
我喜欢那座雕像
I like the statue.
比他在世时要好看多了
A lot better looking than he was when he was alive, though.
不那么猥琐  油腻了
A little less weaselly, less greasy, maybe.
你知道这是什么吗
Do you know what this is?
苏尔特尔的头骨  厉害的武器啊
The skull of Surtur. That's a formidable weapon!
帮个忙  把这个锁进地堡
Do me a favor. Lock this away in a vault
免得它变成巨大的怪物
so it doesn't turn into a giant monster
毁了整个星球
and destroy the whole planet.
谢谢  亲爱的
Thank you, dear.
那么你要回米德加德了吗
So it's back to Midgard for you, is it?
不
Nope.
我最近老做同一个梦
I've been having this reoccurring dream lately.
每晚上  我都看到阿斯加德化为灰烬
Every night, I see Asgard fall into ruins.
不过是个没意义的梦
That's just a silly dream,
说明你的想象力太丰富了
signs of an overactive imagination.
或许吧
Possibly.
但我决定出去勘察一番
But then I decide to go out there and investigate.
结果发现  九大王国一片混乱
And what do I find, but the Nine Realms completely in chaos.
阿斯加德的敌人集结起来  阴谋致我们于死地
Enemies of Asgard assembling, plotting our demise,
而你  奥丁  九大王国的保护者
all while you, Odin, the protector of those Nine Realms,
却穿着浴袍坐在这里  吃着葡萄
are sitting here in your bathrobe, eating grapes.
是啊  我们最好尊重邻居的自由
Yes, it is best to respect our neighbors' freedom.
是啊  被屠杀的自由
Yes, of course, the freedom to be massacred.
是啊  而且  我一直忙着呢
Yes, besides I've been rather busy myself.
看剧
Watching theater.
委员会会议  安全理事会会议
Well, board meetings, and security council meetings...
-你真要逼我这么做吗  -做什么
- You're really gonna make me do it? - Do what?
你很清楚什么都无法阻止雷神之锤回到我手上
You know that nothing will stop Mjolnir as it returns to my hand.
哪怕是你的脸
Not even your face.
你发疯了吧  你会被因此处死的
You've gone quite mad. You'll be executed for this.
那我们就可以在另一边相见了  弟弟
Then I'll see you on the other side, brother.
好吧  我投降
All right, I yield.
看啊
Behold!
托尔
Thor...
-奥丁森  -不
- Odinson. - No.
你就一份工作  就这一份
You had one job. Just the one.
奥丁在哪
Where's Odin?
你就不能别回来吗
You just couldn't stay away, could you?
没有你一切都好好的
Everything was fine without you.
阿斯加德繁荣昌盛  都叫你毁了
Asgard was prospering. You've ruined everything.
-问问他们  -父亲在哪  你杀了他吗
- Ask them. - Where's Father? Did you kill him?
你得到你想要的了  你得到你要的独立了
You had what you wanted. You had the independence you asked for.
好吧  我很清楚他在哪
Okay. I know exactly where he is.
荫萌疗养院
我发誓我就是把他留在这儿的
I swear I left him right here.
是在人行道上
Right here on the sidewalk,
还是在那栋正被拆除的建筑里
or right there where the building is being demolished?
计划得真好
Great planning.
我怎么会知道
How was I supposed to know?
我又不能看到未来  我不是巫师
Can't see into the future. I'm not a witch.
是吗  那你为什么穿得像个巫师
No? Then why do you dress like one?
真不敢相信你还活着
I can't believe you're alive.
我看到你死了  我为你哀悼  为你哭泣
I saw you die. I mourned you, I cried for you.
我好荣幸
I'm honored.
去问他
Ask him.
你可以跟我们合个影吗
Would you mind taking a picture with us?
当然
Sure.
快想想他在哪
Start figuring out where he is.
天呐
Oh, my God.
很遗憾简甩了你
Sorry to hear that Jane dumped you.
她才没甩我
She didn't dump me, you know.
是我甩了她  我们彼此互甩的
I dumped her. It was a mutual dumping.
怎么回事  你在做什么
What's this? What are you doing?
这不是我做的
This isn't me.
洛基
Loki.
布里克街177A
托尔·奥丁森
Thor Odinson.
雷神
God of Thunder.
你可以把伞放下了
You can put down the umbrella.
地球上现在还有男巫了
So, Earth has wizards now?
我们更喜欢被称为"魔法师"
The preferred term is "Master of the Mystic Arts."
别管了
You can leave that now.
好吧  男巫  你是谁  我为什么要在乎
All right, wizard. Who are you? Why should I care?
我是斯蒂芬·斯特兰奇博士
My name is Doctor Stephen Strange,
我有些问题要问你
and I have some questions for you.
请坐
Take a seat.
喝茶吗
Tea?
我不喝茶
I don't drink tea.
你喝什么
What do you drink?
不喝茶
Not tea.
我有一份关注名单
So, I keep a watch list
都是来自其他世界
of individuals and beings from
可能对这个世界构成威胁的人
other realms that may be a threat to this world.
你的领养弟弟  洛基  就是其中之一
Your adopted brother, Loki, is one of those beings.
的确该加上他
He's a worthy inclusion.
为什么带他来这儿
Then why bring him here?
我们在找我父亲
We're looking for my father.
那么  如果我告诉你奥丁在哪
So, if I were to tell you where Odin was,
所有相关人士都会马上回阿斯加德吗
all parties concerned would promptly return to Asgard?
是的  马上
Promptly.
太好了  我来帮你吧
Great! Then I'll help you.
如果你知道他在哪  为什么不联系我
If you knew where he was, why didn't you call me?
我得告诉你  他坚持不许人打搅他
I have to tell you, he was adamant that he not be disturbed.
你父亲说他选择继续被流放
Your father said he had chosen to remain in exile.
而且你没有电话
And you don't have a phone.
是啊  我没有电话
No, I don't have a phone,
但你可以发个
but you could have sent
电子信件  叫电邮
an electronic letter. It's called an email.
-嗯  你有电脑吗  -没有  干吗用
- Yeah, do you have a computer? - No. What for?
总之  我父亲不再被流放了
Anyway, my father is no longer in exile.
麻烦你告诉我他在哪  我就能带他回家了
So if you could tell me where he is, I can take him home.
没问题  他在挪威
Gladly. He's in Norway.
我就是查看一下
I'm just seeing
这则咒语是否要为阿斯加德人做些调整
whether this incantation requires any Asgardian modifications.
不用
Nope.
我们不需要那个
We don't need that.
你能不能别那么做了
Will you stop doing that?
我可以...我需要你一根头发
Can I... I need just one strand of your hair.
我告诉你  我的头发是碰不得的
Let me explain something. My hair is not to be meddled with.
我们完全可以用走的
We could have just walked.
他在等你了
He's waiting for you.
好
All right.
别忘了你的伞
Don't forget your umbrella.
是啊
Yes.
抱歉
Sorry.
来了
There we go.
我还得要回我弟弟
I suppose I'll need my brother back.
对了  好的
Yeah. Right.
我都下落30分钟了
I have been falling for 30 minutes!
他就交给你了
You can handle him from here.
好的  非常感谢你帮忙
Yes. Of course. Thank you very much for your help.
祝你好运
Good luck.
"交给你"  你是谁
Handle me? Who are you?
洛基
Loki.
你是什么术士吗
You think you're some kind of sorcerer?
你个二流货  别以为你...
Don't think for one minute, you second-rate...
好吧  再见
All right. Bye-bye.
父亲
Father?
看看这里  多美
Look at this place. It's beautiful.
父亲  是我们
Father, it's us.
我的儿子们
My sons.
我一直在等你们
I've been waiting for you.
我知道  我们来接你回家了
I know. We've come to take you home.
回家  是啊
Home, yes.
你们母亲  她在召唤我
Your mother, she calls me.
你们听到了吗
Do you hear it?
洛基  解除你的魔法
Loki, lift your magic.
我花了好久才摆脱你的咒语
Took me quite a while to break free from your spell.
弗丽嘉会为你自豪的
Frigga would have been proud.
过来陪我坐下  我没多少时间了
Come and sit with me. I don't have much time.
我知道我们辜负了你
I know we failed you.
但我们可以弥补的
But we can make this right.
是我辜负了你们
I failed you.
诸神黄昏已经到来
It is upon us. Ragnarok.
不  我阻止了诸神黄昏  我了结了苏尔特尔
No, I've stopped Ragnarok. I put an end to Surtur.
不
No.
已经开始了  她要来了
It has already begun. She's coming.
我的生命是唯一遏制着她的东西
My life was all that held her back.
但我大限将至
But my time has come.
我无法再抵住她了
I cannot keep her away any longer.
父亲  你在说谁
Father, who are you talking about?
死亡女神  海拉
Goddess of Death. Hela.
我的长女
My firstborn.
你姐姐
Your sister.
什么
Your what?
她的暴力欲望膨胀到我无法控制
Her violent appetites grew beyond my control.
我无法阻止她  就囚禁了她  把她关了起来
I couldn't stop her, so I imprisoned her. Locked her away.
她从阿斯加德汲取力量
She draws her strength from Asgard,
等她到了那里  她的力量就将无可限量
and once she gets there, her powers will be limitless.
不管她是什么  我们可以一同阻止她
Whatever she is, we can stop her together.
我们可以一同对抗她
We can face her together.
不行的
No, we won't.
我已走上了另一条路
I'm on a different path now.
这件事你们得独自面对了
This you must face alone.
我爱你们  我的儿子
I love you, my sons.
看啊
Look at that.
记住这地方
Remember this place.
家园
Home.
哥哥
Brother.
这都怪你
This was your doing.
他死了啊
So he's gone.
真可惜  我还挺想看到那一幕的
That's a shame. I would've liked to have seen that.
你就是海拉吧
You must be Hela.
我是托尔  奥丁之子
I'm Thor, son of Odin.
是吗  你长得不像他
Really? You don't look like him.
或许我们可以商量一下
Perhaps we can come to an arrangement.
你口气像他
You sound like him.
跪下
Kneel.
你说什么
Beg your pardon?
跪下
Kneel.
拜见你的女王
Before your queen.
别指望了
I don't think so.
不可能
It's not possible.
亲爱的  你根本想象不到我都能做什么
Darling, you have no idea what's possible.
带我们回去
Bring us back!
不
No!
洛基
Loki!
你是谁  你把托尔怎么了
Who are you? What have you done with Thor?
我是海拉
I'm Hela.
我就是个扫地的
I'm just a janitor.
你看上去像个求生本能强烈的机灵鬼
You look like a smart boy with good survival instincts.
想要份工作吗
How would you like a job?
你是个战士吗
Are you a fighter?
还是食物
Or are you food?
我就是路过
I'm just passing through.
是食物
It is food.
跪下
On your knees.
他是我的
He's mine.
等等
Wait!
他是我的
He's mine.
如果你们想要他  得过我这关
So if you want him, you go through me.
但我们已经得到他了
But we've already got him.
那好吧  我就先过你们这关
All right, then. I guess I go through you.
又来食物了
More food.
谢谢
Thank you.
拾荒者142号  我需要进门并觐见老大
Scrapper 142. I need clearance and an audience with the boss.
我带来了特别的东西
I've got something special.
你要带我去哪
Where are you taking me?
回答我
Answer me!
我是托尔  奥丁之子  我得回阿斯加德
I am Thor, son of Odin. I need to get back to Asgard.
非常抱歉  王子殿下
Many apologies, your majesty.
我发现  你们并不认识我
It's come to my attention that you don't know who I am.
我是海拉  奥丁的长女
I am Hela, Odin's firstborn,
阿斯加德大军的统帅
the commander of the Legions of Asgard,
王位的合法继承人  死亡女神
the rightful heir to the throne, and the Goddess of Death.
我父亲已死
My father is dead.
两位王子也是  不客气
As are the princes. You're welcome.
我们曾在宇宙中坐拥无上力量
We were once the seat of absolute power in the cosmos.
我们的地位无可匹及
Our supremacy was unchallenged.
但奥丁却止步于九大王国
Yet Odin stopped at Nine Realms.
我们的命运是统治所有其他王国
Our destiny is to rule over all others.
我是来恢复那份权势的
And I am here to restore that power.
给我跪下
Kneel before me
加入我  与我一起踏上伟大的征途
and rise into the ranks of my great conquest.
不管你是谁
Whoever you are,
不管你做了什么  马上投降
whatever you've done, surrender now!
否则我们绝不留情
Or we will show you no mercy.
不管我是谁  我刚刚说话你听没听啊
Whoever I am? Did you listen to a word I said?
这是你最后的警告
This is your last warning!
我以为你们会乐意见到我呢
I thought you'd be happy to see me.
好吧
Fine.
进攻
Charge!
我真怀念这个
I've missed this.
不过  真是可惜
Still, it's a shame.
好战士白白枉死
Good soldiers dying for nothing,
就因为他们看不到未来
all because they couldn't see the future.
悲哀
Sad.
看  他还活着
Look, still alive.
改主意了吗
Change of heart?
滚回你爬出来的山洞去吧
Go back to whatever cave you crept out of.
你个女魔头
You evil demoness!
去看看我的王宫吧
Let's go see my palace.
别担心  你已被找到
Fear not, for you are found.
你到家了  再也回不去了
You are home, and there is no going back.
没人能离开此地
No one leaves this place.
但这里是什么地方
But what is this place?
这里是  萨卡
The answer is Sakaar.
被宇宙传送门环绕
Surrounded by cosmic gateways,
萨卡位于已知和未知世界的边缘
Sakaar lives on the edge of the known and unknown.
这里收集了所有迷失  不被爱的东西
It is the collection point for all lost and unloved things.
比如你
Like you.
但在萨卡  你是重要的
But here on Sakaar, you are significant.
你是有价值的
You are valuable.
你是被爱的
Here you are loved.
怎么回事
What the hell?
没人比宗师更爱你了
And no one loves you more than the Grandmaster.
他是最初的  第一个迷失  第一个被找到的人
He is the original, the first lost and the first found.
萨卡的创始人
The creator of Sakaar,
冠军格斗之父
and father of the Contest of Champions.
虽然你曾经一文不名  但现在你有了身份
Where once you were nothing, now you are something.
你是宗师的财产
You are the property of the Grandmaster.
恭喜
Congratulations!
你将在5秒后见到宗师
You will meet the Grandmaster in five seconds.
准备好
Prepare yourself.
你将见到宗师
You are now meeting the Grandmaster.
他真棒  是个"他"吧
He's wonderful. It is a he?
是的
It is a he.
嗯
Yeah.
我就喜欢你过来  142
I love when you come to visit, 142.
你总给我带最好的东西来
You bring me the best stuff.
托佩兹  每次我们聊起拾荒者142号
Whenever we get to talking, Topaz, about Scrapper 142,
我都怎么说  "她是..."  B开头的词
what do I always say? "She is the..." And it starts with a "B."
垃圾
Trash.
不  不是垃圾
No, not trash.
你是就等着那么说她吗
Were you waiting just to call her that?
都不是B开头的词
It doesn't start with a "B."
酒鬼婆娘
Booze hag.
抱歉  不是  "最好的"
I'm so sorry. No, "Best."
我是想说"最好的"
I was thinking about "Best."
因为我总说你是最好的
'Cause I always say you're the best.
她为我带来了我的格斗冠军呢
She brought me my beloved champion, you know.
每次她来你都这么说
You say that every time she's here.
你今天带来的是什么  告诉我
What have you brought today? Tell me.
参赛者
A contender.
什么
A what?
我得凑近点  我要凑近看看他
I need to go closer. I want to get a closer look at this.
可以把我往前推推吗  谢谢
Can you take us closer? Thank you.
给她钱
Pay this lady.
给我等一下
Just wait a damn minute.
我可不是卖品
I'm not for sale.
天呐  他挺有斗志
Man, he's a fighter.
我要一千万
I take 10 million.
告诉她那是做梦
Tell her she's dreaming.
老天  给她钱吧
For heaven's sakes, transfer the units.
你会付出代价的
You'll pay for this.
不  是别人付我钱
No, I got paid for this.
我想知道的是
Here's what I wanna know.
你是谁
Who are you?
我是雷神
I am the God of Thunder.
我没听到雷声
I didn't hear any thunder,
但你手上的是电火花吗
but out of your fingers, was that sparkles?
我们找到你表亲了
We've located your cousin.
太好了
Good!
来吧  你会喜欢这个的
Yeah, come on. I think you're gonna like this.
他在这儿呢
There he is.
表弟
Hey, cuz.
我们差点没找到你  你藏起来了吗
We almost couldn't find you. What, you been hiding?
那么
So...
求你
Please.
对不起
I'm sorry.
嗯
Yeah.
卡洛
Carlo...
我赦免你
I pardon you.
谢谢
Thank you.
你被赦免了
You're officially pardoned.
免了生命
From life.
救命
Help me.
天呐
Oh, my God!
流到我脚下了  看啊
I'm stepping in it. I'm stepping in it. Look!
好臭
The smell.
这是什么味儿
What does it smell like?
烤焦的吐司
Burnt toast.
我怎么这么没礼貌
What happened to my manners?
我还没好好自我介绍呢
I haven't properly introduced myself.
来吧  跟我来
Come on. Follow me.
我叫宗师
My name is Grandmaster.
我主持一项
I preside over a little
滑稽表演  叫做冠军格斗
harlequinade called the Contest of Champions.
来自各处的人  都会不情愿地参与其中
People come from far and wide to unwillingly participate in it.
而你  我的朋友  可以加入新卡司
And you, my friend, might just be part of the new cast.
怎么样
What do you say to that?
我们不是朋友  我也不在乎你的游戏
We're not friends and I don't give a shit about your games.
我要回阿斯加德
I'm going back to Asgard.
阿屎加德
Ass-gard.
一  二  三  四
One, two, three, four.
我下方有个时间空间的虫洞
There was a wormhole in space and time beneath me.
于是  我放手了
At that moment, I let go.
洛基
Loki?
Loki! Loki!
过来
Over here. Over here.
-失陪一下  -洛基
- Excuse me one second. - Loki!
-干什么  -你还活着
- What? - You're alive?
-我当然还活着  -你怎么来了
- Yes, of course I'm alive. - What are you doing here?
这话什么意思
What do you mean, what am I doing?
我被困在这张破椅子上了
I'm stuck in this stupid chair.
-你怎么没坐椅子  -没人让我坐椅子
- Where's your chair? - I didn't get a chair.
-帮我从这椅子上起来  -不行
- Get me out of this one. - I can't.
-帮我起来  -不行
- Get me out. - I can't.
什么
What?
我跟那个宗师交了朋友
I've made friends with this man. He's called the Grandmaster.
-他是个疯子  -我赢得了他的好感
- He's crazy! - I've gained his favor.
彩虹桥几周前把我丢到了这里
The Bifrost brought me out here weeks ago.
-几周前  -是啊
- Weeks ago? - Yes.
我才刚到
I just got here.
你们在小声说什么呢
What are you whispering about?
这里的时间规律很不一样
Time works real different around these parts.
在别的世界上  我都该几百万岁了
On any other world, I'd be, like, millions of years old.
但在萨卡上
But here on Sakaar...
不管怎样  你认识这个...
In any case, you know this...
你称自己为雷王是吧
You call yourself Lord of Thunder?
雷神  告诉他
God of Thunder. Tell him.
我这辈子从未见过这个人
I've never met this man in my life.
-他是我弟弟  -领养的
- He's my brother. - Adopted.
他能不能打
Is he any kind of a fighter?
你把我脖子上的东西拿走  我就打给你看看
You take this thing out of my neck and I'll show you.
瞧瞧  他在威胁我呢
Now, listen to that. He's threatening me.
小火花  事情是这样的
Hey, Sparkles, here's the deal.
如果你想回到那个二死堡还是什么的地方
If you wanna get back to Ass-place, Assberg...
阿斯加德
Asgard.
任何参赛者  只要能打败我的冠军
Any contender who defeats my champion,
就能赢得自由
their freedom they shall win.
好啊  那就给我指个路
Fine. Then point me in the direction
要我去揍的人在哪里
of whoever's ass I have to kick!
这才是我的参赛者
That's what I call, contender.
这边走  大王
Direction would be this way, Lord.
洛基
Loki!
放松点  哥们
Take it easy, man.
这边呢
Over here.
向你招手的一堆石头
The pile of rocks waving at you. Here.
是的  我其实是有生命的
Yeah, I'm actually a thing. I'm a being.
请允许我做个自我介绍
Allow me to introduce myself.
我叫寇格  我算是这里的领导吧
My name is Korg. I'm kind of like the leader in here.
你也能看出来  我是石头做的
I'm made of rocks, as you can see.
但不要被我的外表吓到
But don't let that intimidate you.
你不用害怕  除非你是剪刀做的
You don't need to be afraid unless you're made of scissors.
就是跟你开个石头剪刀布的小玩笑
Just a little rock-paper-scissor joke for you.
这是我的好朋友  米克
This is my very good friend over here, Miek.
他是只有剪刀手的昆虫
He's an insect and has knives for hands.
你是克努南人  对吗
You're a Kronan, aren't you?
-没错  -你怎么会落到这里
- That I am. - How'd you end up in here?
我试图发动革命来着
Well, I tried to start a revolution,
但没做好宣传工作
but didn't print enough pamphlets.
所以几乎没人参加
So hardly anyone turned up,
除了我妈妈和她那讨厌的男朋友
except for my mum and her boyfriend, who I hate.
作为惩罚  我被迫来到这里做个角斗士
As punishment, I was forced to be in here and become a gladiator.
简直是个宣传灾难
Bit of a promotional disaster, that one.
但我其实在策划另一场革命
But I'm actually organizing another revolution.
我不知道你是不是感兴趣
I don't know if you'd be interested in something like that.
你觉得怎么样
Do you reckon you'd be interested?
你怎么会...
How did you...
是啊  这个地方其实是个圈
Yeah, no. This whole thing is a circle.
但不是真正的圈  更像是个恐怖怪圈
But not a real circle, more like a freaky circle.
这没道理
This doesn't make any sense.
是啊  这里就是不讲道理的
No, nothing makes sense here, man.
没道理就是这里的道理
The only thing that does make sense is that nothing makes sense.
这里有人跟宗师的冠军打过吗
Has anyone here fought the Grandmaster's champion?
道格打过
Doug has.
道格
Doug!
这就是命  道格已经死了
Our luck, Doug's dead.
对了  跟宗师的冠军打过的人都死掉了
That's right. Everyone who fights the Grandmaster's champion perishes.
你呢  你是石头做的
What about you? You're made of rocks.
会死掉的石头  看啊  又掉一块
Perishable rock. There you go. Another one gone.
我只是小打小闹
Yeah, no, I just do the smaller fights,
暖暖场之类的
warm up the crowd and whatnot.
等等  你不是要去跟他打吧
Wait. You're not gonna face him, are you?
没错
Yes, I am.
我要跟他打  打赢他  然后离开这鬼地方
Gonna fight him, win, and get the hell out of this place.
道格以前就这么说
That's exactly what Doug used to say.
回见  新道格
See you later, new Doug.
没人记得我吗
Does no one remember me?
没人学过我们的历史吗
Has no one been taught our history?
看看这些谎言
Look at these lies.
高脚杯  花园聚会
Goblets and garden parties?
和平协议
Peace treaties?
奥丁...
Odin...
为成果骄傲
Proud to have it,
却觉得手段可耻
ashamed of how he got it.
我们曾势不可挡
We were unstoppable.
在扩张阿斯加德帝国时  我曾是他的武器
I was his weapon in the conquest that built Asgard's empire.
我们征服了一个又一个王国
One by one, the realms became ours.
然后  就因为我的野心比他更大
But then, simply because my ambition outgrew his,
他就将我放逐  囚禁
he banished me, caged me,
像只野兽一样把我锁了起来
locked me away like an animal.
在那之前  阿斯加德的战士是受尊敬的
Before that, Asgard's warriors were honored,
他们的遗体像英雄那样葬在这宫殿下面
their bodies buried as heroes beneath this very palace.
-奥丁的宝藏  -赝品
- Odin's treasures. - Fake.
这里大部分的东西都是赝品
Most of the stuff in here is fake.
或者没用
Or weak.
比我以为的要小
Smaller than I thought it would be.
这个还可以
That's not bad.
但是这个...
But this...
永恒烈火
The Eternal Flame.
想看看真正的力量是什么样子吗
Want to see what true power really looks like?
亲爱的芬里斯  他们对你做了什么
Fenris, my darling, what have they done to you?
永恒烈火将让你们重生
With the Eternal Flame, you are reborn.
我好想你
I've missed you.
我想念你们大家
I've missed you all.
奥丁
Odin,
我愿你升入英灵殿
I bid you take your place in the halls of Valhalla,
勇者将在那里永生
where the brave shall live forever.
我们应该高兴而不是哀伤
Nor shall we mourn but rejoice,
因为他们死得光荣
for those that have died the glorious death.
扎心  对吗
Hurts, doesn't it?
被欺骗的感觉
Being lied to.
告诉你是一回事  然后你发现那都是假的
Being told you're one thing and then learning it's all a fiction.
你不会以为我真的会来这里见你吧
You didn't think I'd really come and see you, did you?
这地方太恶心了
This place is disgusting.
你是不想要我帮忙吗
Does this mean you don't want my help?
我不能失去我在宗师身边的地位
Look, I couldn't jeopardize my position with the Grandmaster.
我为赢得他的信任很费心力
It took me time to win his trust.
他是个疯子  但也是有办法应付的
He's a lunatic, but he can be amenable.
我是想告诉你
What I'm telling you is,
你可以跟我一起服侍宗师
you could join me at the Grandmaster's side.
也许将来  宗师会出事  然后...
Perhaps, in time, an accident befalls the Grandmaster, and then...
你不是真在考虑回去吧
You're not seriously thinking of going back, are you?
我们姐姐像砸玻璃一样轻松毁了你的锤子
Our sister destroyed your hammer like a piece of glass.
她比我们都强  她比你强
She's stronger than both of us. She's stronger than you.
你一丝机会都没有
You don't stand a chance.
你明白我什么意思吗
Do you understand what I'm saying here?
好吧
Fine.
那我得单干了
I guess I'll just have to go it alone.
一如既往
Like I've always done.
你能不能说点什么
Would you say something?
说话啊
Say something!
你要我说什么
What would you like me to say?
你装死
You faked your own death,
偷了王位  剥夺了奥丁的法力
you stole the throne, stripped Odin of his power,
把他留在地球上等死  放出了死亡女神
stranded him on Earth to die, releasing the Goddess of Death.
这些够不够
Have I said enough
还是你要我继续翻两天之前的旧账
or would you like me to go back further than the past two days?
我还没见过他口中这个宠儿冠军
You know, I haven't seen this beloved champion he talks of,
但听说他野蛮得吓人
but I've heard he is astonishingly savage.
明天的格斗  我下了很大的注压你输
I've placed a large wager against you tomorrow.
别让我失望
Don't let me down.
滚开  鬼
Piss off, ghost!
他消失了
He's freaking gone.
恶心
Yuck!
这上面还留着不知谁的毛发和血
There's still someone's hair and blood all over this.
伙计们  格斗完能不能清理下武器啊
Guys, can you clean up the weapons once you finish your fight?
恶心的懒蛋
Disgusting slobs.
托尔  用大木叉子吗
Thor, wanna use a big wooden fork?
不了
No.
是啊  不太实用
Yeah, not really useful.
除非你要打挤成一团的
Unless you're fighting off three vampires
三个吸血鬼
that were huddled together.
真希望我的锤子还在
I really wish I had my hammer.
锤子
Hammer?
很特别
Quite unique.
是用濒死星球内核的特别金属制成
It was made from this special metal from the heart of a dying star.
我快速抡它
And when I spun it really, really fast,
就能飞起来
it gave me the ability to fly.
你骑在锤子上
You rode a hammer?
不  不是骑在上面
No, I didn't ride the hammer.
它骑在你背上
The hammer rode you on your back?
不  我快速抡它
No. I used to spin it really fast,
它就会把我带起来...
and it would pull me off the...
天啊  锤子给你撸吗
Oh, my God. A hammer pulled you off?
把我带离地面  它会带我离开地面
The ground. It would pull me off the ground,
带我升入空中  我就能飞了
up into the air, and I would fly.
我把它扔出去  它总能回到我手中
Every time I threw it, it would always come back to me.
你和这把锤子的关系好像很特殊
Sounds like you had a pretty special and intimate relationship
很亲密
with this hammer
失去它堪比失去爱人
and that losing it was almost comparable to losing a loved one.
这么说挺温馨的
That's a nice way of putting it.
我说了这些是我的
I said they're mine.
看  就是她把我抓来的
See her, that's the one that put me in here.
是啊  拾荒者142号
Yeah. Scrapper 142.
要小心这些阿斯加德人
Gotta watch out for those Asgardians, man.
命硬得很
They are hard to perish.
阿斯加德人
Asgardian?
别用那玩意电我  我有话要说
Do not zap me with that thing. I just wanna talk.
阿斯加德有危险了
Asgard is in danger.
天啊  你是女武神
My God, you're a Valkyrie.
我小时候还想当女武神
I used to wanna be a Valkyrie when I was younger,
但之后我发现你们都是女的
until I found out that you were all women.
是女的没什么不好  我爱女人
There's nothing wrong with women, of course. I love women.
有时太爱了
Sometimes a little too much.
不是猥琐的那种  是尊重的欣赏
Not in a creepy way, just more of a respectful appreciation.
能有一支女武士组成的精英部队真的很不错
I think it's great that there is an elite force of women warriors.
是时候了
It's about time.
-你说完没  -雷王  该你了
- Are you done? - Lord of Thunder, you're up.
求你  帮帮我  我需要你的帮助
Please, help me. I need your help.
再见
Bye.
好吧  那你不是叛徒就是懦夫
Fine, then you must be a traitor or a coward.
因为女武神都发过誓要保卫王权
Because the Valkyrie is sworn to protect the throne.
听仔细了  殿下  这是萨卡  不是阿斯加德
Listen closely, your majesty. This is Sakaar, not Asgard.
我是拾荒者  不是女武神
And I'm a Scrapper, not a Valkyrie.
带他过来收拾一下
Bring him in for processing.
没人能逃出这里  所以你反正也是个死
And no one escapes this place. So you're gonna die anyway.
你别动
Now, don't you move.
我的手不如以前稳了
My hands ain't as steady as they used to be.
以奥丁的胡子起誓  你不准剪我的头发
By Odin's beard, you shall not cut my hair,
不然就会尝到托尔之怒的滋味
lest you feel the wrath of the mighty Thor.
求你了  求你了  好心人  别剪我头发
Please. Please, kind sir, do not cut my hair.
求你  不要
Please! No!
不
No!
看看你们  今晚比赛多么精彩
Look at all of you. What a show! What a night!
谁觉得开心
Who's having fun?
我是你们的主持人
Please, I'm your host.
请掌声感谢所有赛前战的格斗者
Big round of applause for all of our undercard competitors,
他们今天死得真可怕
who today died so gruesomely.
比赛真棒
Good sports.
今晚比赛多么精彩
What a show! What a night!
我们都是为格斗而来的
This is what you've come for, and so have I.
现在  不再耽搁
And now, without further ado,
压轴比赛开始了
it's main event time.
虽是首次登场  但却很有潜力
Making his first appearance, though he looks quite promising,
有点绝招
got a couple of tricks up his sleeve.
我不再多说了  你们来自己判断
I'll say no more, see what you think.
女士们先生们  有请
Ladies and gentlemen, I give you...
雷王
Lord of Thunder.
小心他的手指  会放火花
Watch out for his fingers. They make sparks.
好了  来吧
Okay, this is it.
我们准备欢迎这家伙吧  他来咯
Let's get ready to welcome this guy. Here he comes.
他这个家伙
He is a creature.
我们要怎么说呢
What can we say about him?
他很特别  独一无二
Well, he's unique. There's none like him.
我觉得跟他有特别的感情
I feel a special connection with him.
他从未有败绩
He's undefeated.
是连胜者
He's the reigning.
是卫冕方
He's the defending.
女士们先生们
Ladies and gentlemen...
有请
I give you...
无敌的
Your Incredible...
绿巨人
Hulk!
太好了
Yes!
我得离开这个星球
I have to get off this planet.
你想去哪啊
Where you going?
我俩认识
We know each other.
他是我战友
He's a friend from work.
你去哪了
Where have you been?
大家都以为你死了
Everybody thought you were dead.
我们上次一别后发生了好多事
But so much has happened since I last saw you.
我失去了锤子
I lost my hammer.
就昨天  还记忆犹新的
Like, yesterday, so that's still pretty fresh.
洛基还活着  相信吗
Loki. Loki's alive. Can you believe it?
他就在上面
He's up there.
洛基  看这是谁
Loki! Look who it is!
班纳  真没想到我会这么说
Banner, I never thought I would say this,
但我见到你可真高兴
but I'm happy to see you.
绿巨人  绿巨人
Hulk! Hulk! Hulk!
班纳
Banner.
Banner!
不是班纳  只有绿巨人
No Banner. Only Hulk.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
是我啊  托尔
It's me. It's Thor!
班纳  我们是朋友啊
Banner, we're friends.
这真是疯了  我不想伤你
This is crazy. I don't want to hurt you!
这就对了  这才像话
Here we go. Here we go.
什么
What?
大块头
Hey, big guy.
太阳快下山了
The sun's getting real low.
没错  太阳要下山了
That's it. The sun's going down.
我不会再伤害你了
I won't hurt you anymore.
没人会伤害你了
No one will.
没错
Yes!
就是这感觉
That's how it feels!
我就是太喜欢这项运动了
I'm just a huge fan of the sport.
好吧  不管了
All right. Screw it.
我知道你还在的  班纳
I know you're in there, Banner.
我会把你逼出来的
I'll get you out!
你是怎么了  真让我下不来台
What's the matter with you? You're embarrassing me!
我还跟他们说我们是朋友
I told them we were friends!
雷哥  雷哥
Thunder! Thunder! Thunder!
又一天  又一个道格
Another day, another Doug.
那是什么声音
What is that noise?
民众并没有乖乖听话
The common folk aren't exactly falling in line.
有抵抗者想撞倒大门
There's a resistance trying to knock down the front gates.
说说你自己吧  斯科尔奇
Tell me about yourself, Skurge.
我爸是个石匠  我妈是...
Well, me dad was a stonemason. Me mum was...
嗯  打住吧  我的意思是
Right, yeah, I'll just stop you there. What I meant was,
你的野心是什么
what's your ambition?
我只想要个机会证明自己
I just want a chance to prove myself.
承认
Recognition.
我年轻时
When I was young,
每位伟大国王都有个处刑人
every great king had an executioner.
不仅仅是进行处刑
Not just to execute people,
也执行国王的愿景
but also to execute their vision.
但主要还是做处刑的
But mainly to execute people.
但  这仍是无上光荣
Still, it was a great honor.
我曾是奥丁的处刑人
I was Odin's executioner.
你就做我的处刑人
And you shall be my executioner.
我们开始征程吧
Let's begin our conquest.
斯科尔奇  剑呢
Skurge, where's the sword?
那把剑是打开彩虹桥的钥匙
That sword is the key to opening the Bifrost.
你提到的那些人
Those people you mentioned,
那些不肯乖乖就范的
the ones who aren't falling into line...
把他们都抓起来
Round them up.
借过
Excuse me.
抱歉了  那些玩意到处都是
Sorry about that. These bloody things are everywhere.
走吧
Come on.
你们在这里是安全的
You'll be safe here.
我们没事了吧
Are we cool?
绿巨人洗热浴盆
It's Hulk in a hot tub.
你这样多久了
So how long have you been like that?
什么样
Like what?
这样  大块头  绿色的  呆头呆脑
Like this. Big, and green, and stupid.
绿巨人一直是绿巨人
Hulk always Hulk.
你怎么到这儿的
How'd you get here?
靠赢
Winning.
你是说作弊吧
You mean cheating?
你赢的时候  对手也都有这玩意吗
Were they wearing one of these when you won?
你怎么来到这儿的
How'd you arrive here?
昆式战斗机
Quinjet.
很好  那架昆式战斗机现在在哪
Yes. Now, where is the Quinjet now?
你没穿衣服
That's naked.
他没穿衣服
He's very naked.
这下忘不掉了
It's in my brain now.
昆式战斗机
Quinjet.
太好了
Yes!
我要带咱们离开
I'm getting us out of here.
这个糟糕的地方
This terrible, awful place.
你会喜欢阿斯加德的
You're gonna love Asgard.
很大  还金闪闪的
It's big. It's golden. Shiny.
绿巨人不走
Hulk stay.
不不  我的人民需要我回阿斯加德
No, no, no. My people need me to get back to Asgard.
我们得阻止诸神黄昏
We must prevent Ragnarok.
诸神黄昏
Ragnarok?
我家园的毁灭预言
The prophesied death of my home world.
世界末日  一切终结
The end of days, it's the end of...
如果你帮我回阿斯加德
If you help me get back to Asgard,
我可以帮你回地球
I can help you get back to Earth.
地球恨绿巨人
Earth hate Hulk.
地球爱绿巨人  他们爱死你了
Earth loves Hulk. They love you.
你是复仇者联盟成员  我们的队友  朋友
You're one of the Avengers. One of the team, one of our friends.
朋友就该如此  彼此支持
This is what friends do. They support each other.
你是班纳的朋友
You're Banner's friend.
我才不是班纳的朋友  我更喜欢你
I'm not Banner's friend. I prefer you.
班纳的朋友
Banner's friend.
我都不喜欢班纳
I don't even like Banner.
"我喜欢数字  科学什么的"
"I'm into numbers and science and stuff."
托尔走  绿巨人留下
Thor go. Hulk stay.
好吧
Fine.
留下吧
Stay here.
破地方  难看死了
Stupid place. It's hideous, by the way.
又是红  又是白  选个颜色吧  真荒唐
The red, the white. Just pick a color. Ridiculous.
砸扁你
Smash you.
你才没砸扁什么  那场角斗我赢了
You didn't smash anything. I won that fight.
-我砸扁了你  -好吧
- I smashed you. - Yeah, sure, sure.
-小手臂  -什么
- Baby arms. - What?
小个子
Baby.
白痴  你个幼稚鬼
Moron! You big child.
托尔走
Thor go!
我在走
I am going.
托尔再走
Thor go again.
托尔在家了
Thor home.
绿巨人训练
Hulk trains.
好啊  祝你开心
That's great. Have fun.
-好啊  大块头  -生气姑娘
- Hey, big guy. - Angry girl.
你都干什么呢
What have you been up to?
获胜
Winning.
海姆达尔  我知道你看得到我
Heimdall, I know you can see me.
我需要你帮我
I need you to help me.
帮我看到
Help me see.
我看得到你  但你在很远的地方
I see you, but you're far away.
这里怎么回事
What's going on here?
自己来看吧
Come see for yourself.
我在祖先建造的要塞里庇护大家
I'm providing refuge in a stronghold built by our ancestors.
但如果抵挡不住  我们只能靠彩虹桥逃跑
But if the garrison falls, our only escape is Bifrost.
你想要疏散整个阿斯加德
You're talking about evacuating Asgard?
如果留下我们都活不久
We won't last long if we stay.
她汲取阿斯加德的力量  每天都更强大
She draws her power from Asgard and grows stronger every day.
走吧
Come on.
海拉很贪婪
Hela is ravenous.
如果我放走了她
If I let her leave,
她会吞噬整个九大王国甚至宇宙
she'll consume Nine Realms and all the cosmos.
我们需要你
We need you.
我在想办法了  但我都不知道自己在哪
I'm working on it. But I don't even know where the hell I am.
你所在的星球周围都是传送门  穿过其中一个
You're on a planet surrounded by doorways. Go through one.
-哪个  -大的那个
- Which one? - The big one.
托尔难过
Thor sad.
闭嘴
Shut up.
托尔难过
Thor sad.
我不难过  你个白痴
I'm not sad, you idiot.
我在生气
I'm pissed off!
愤怒  我失去了父亲
Angry. I lost my father.
我失去了锤子
I lost my hammer.
-唧唧歪歪  像个孩子  -你都没认真听
- Whining and crying. Cry like baby. - You're not even listening.
别踢东西
Don't kick stuff.
你真不够朋友
You're being a really bad friend.
你才不够朋友
You bad friend!
-你知道我们怎么喊你吗  -不知道
- You know what we call you? - No.
我们喊你蠢复仇者
We call you the stupid Avenger.
你是小复仇者
You're tiny Avenger!
你疯了吗
What, are you crazy?
是啊
Yes.
知道吗  地球是恨你
You know what? Earth does hate you.
不要
No.
很抱歉我说了那些话
I'm sorry I said those things.
你不是蠢复仇者
You're not the stupid Avenger.
没人喊你蠢复仇者
Nobody calls you the stupid Avenger.
没事
It's okay.
你不能随便冲人仍盾牌
You just can't go around throwing shields at people.
差点杀了我
Could have killed me.
我知道  对不起  我总是好生气
I know. I'm sorry. I just get so angry all the time.
绿巨人总是很生气
Hulk always, always angry.
我知道  我们是一样的
I know. We're the same, you and I.
我们就是俩鲁莽的傻瓜
We're just a couple of hot-headed fools.
是啊  一样  绿巨人是火  托尔是水
Yeah, same. Hulk like fire, Thor like water.
我们都是火
We're kind of both like fire.
但绿巨人是真火
But Hulk like real fire.
绿巨人是烈火
Hulk like raging fire.
托尔是阴燃火
Thor like smoldering fire.
绿巨人  我需要你帮我个忙
Hulk, I need you to do something for me.
生气姑娘
Angry girl.
怎么了  你...
What's going on? What are you...
你就蠢到看不出
You're so thick-headed that you can't tell
人家远远躲到了宇宙尽头
when someone's hiding all the way across the universe
就是不想被打扰吗
and wants to be left alone?
-我们得谈谈  -不  你想跟我谈
- We need to talk. - No, you wanna talk to me.
我需要她留下
I need her to stay.
留下
Stay?
挡住
Block.
留下
Stay.
-拜托  -拜托
- Please. - Please.
好吧
All right.
这样吧
Here's the deal.
我听你说
I'll listen to you
喝光这个我就走
till this is empty.
阿斯加德有危险  人民在牺牲
Asgard is in danger and people are dying.
我们得回去  我需要你帮忙
We need to get back there. I need your help.
喝完了  再见
Finished. Bye.
奥丁死了
Odin is dead.
死亡女神海拉  入侵了阿斯加德
Hela, the Goddess of Death, has invaded Asgard.
如果海拉回来了  那阿斯加德无望了
If Hela's back, then Asgard's already lost.
我要阻止她
I'm going to stop her.
-一个人吗  -不
- Alone? - Nope.
我在组建一支队伍
I'm putting together a team.
我  你还有大块头
It's me, you, and the big guy.
不  不组队  绿巨人单干
No. No team. Only Hulk.
我和你
It's me and you.
我看是只有你
I think it's only you.
求你  听我说  女武神都是传奇
Please, listen. The Valkyrie are legend.
阿斯加德的精英武士  发誓保护王权
Elite warriors of Asgard sworn to defend the throne.
我不要再次
I'm not getting dragged
被卷入奥丁的家庭纠纷当中
into another one of Odin's family squabbles.
-这话什么意思  -你姐姐
- What's that supposed to mean? - Your sister.
她的力量来自阿斯加德  你也是
Her power comes from Asgard, same as yours.
当奥丁无法控制她的力量
When it grew beyond Odin's control
她就屠杀了王宫里的每个人
she massacred everyone in the palace
企图夺取王位
and tried to seize the throne.
她企图逃离驱逐时
When she tried to escape her banishment
他派女武神去抵抗她
he sent the Valkyrie in to fight her back.
我能生还只是因为
I only survived because...
我已经迎战过她一次了
Look, I already faced her once
那是我还相信王权的时候
back when I believed in the throne,
而我失去了一切
and it cost me everything.
这就是阿斯加德的问题
That's what's wrong with Asgard.
王权  秘密  金色的骗局
The throne, the secrets, the whole golden sham.
我同意
I agree.
别太亲近了
Don't get familiar.
我同意
I agree.
所以我拒绝了王位
That's why I turned down the throne.
但关键不在于王位  而是人民
But this isn't about the crown. This is about the people.
他们要死了  他们也是你的人民
They're dying and they're your people, too.
忘了他们吧
Forget it.
我就做到了
I have.
-好吧  -好
- Okay. - Okay.
-好  很好  -很好
- Good. Great. - Great.
谢谢
Thank you.
-谢什么  -这个
- For what? - For this.
你没看到吧
Didn't see that, did you?
那么...这下好多了
There... That's better.
随你吧
You know, go ahead.
留下  为那个疯子奴役他人
Stay here and enslave people for that lunatic.
继续喝酒  躲藏
Keep drinking, keep hiding.
但我
But me...
我会冲向我的麻烦  而不是逃避它们
I choose to run toward my problems and not away from them.
因为...
Because that's what...
因为  英雄都会这么做
Because that's what heroes do.
朋友留下
Friend stay!
太好了
Yes!
好了
All right.
拜托
Come on.
欢迎  需要语音启动
Welcome. Voice activation required.
托尔
Thor.
访问被拒
Access denied.
托尔  奥丁之子
Thor, son of Odin.
访问被拒
Access denied.
雷神
God of Thunder.
访问被拒
Access denied.
最强大的复仇者
Strongest Avenger.
访问被拒
Access denied.
最强大的复仇者
Strongest Avenger.
访问被拒
Access denied.
讨厌  斯塔克
Damn you, Stark.
惊爆点
Point Break.
欢迎  惊爆点
Welcome, Point Break.
朋友留下
Friend stay!
不不
No, no, no!
站住
Stop!
留下
Stay!
绿巨人  别把飞机都撞烂了
Hulk, stop breaking everything!
别走
Don't go!
好样的  大块头
Nice work, big guy.
我们不知道奥创要去哪
We don't know where Ultron's headed,
但你飞得很高很快
but you're going very high, very fast.
所以  你得驾驶飞机返航
So, I need you to turn this bird around, okay?
隐匿模式追踪不到你
We can't track you in stealth mode,
你得帮帮忙  好吗
so I need you to help me out. Okay?
你得...
I need you to...
不  不要班纳
No! No, Banner!
天呐
Oh, jeez.
班纳
Banner.
没事吧  班纳
You all right, Banner?
太阳快下山了
Sun's going down. Sun's going down.
好了  呼吸
That's it, breathe.
我不会伤害你的
I won't hurt you.
太阳快下山了
Sun's going down.
-托尔  -是啊
- Thor. - Yeah.
你头发怎么了
What happened to your hair?
有个猥琐的老头给我剪了
Some creepy old man cut it off.
-挺帅的  -谢谢
- It looks good. - Thanks.
我们在哪  小娜呢
Where are we? How's Nat?
-小娜肯定挺好的  -她没事吧
- Nat is good, I'm sure. - Is she okay?
-索科威亚呢  -索科威亚
- And what about Sokovia? - Sokovia?
索科威亚  那座城市  我们救下它了吗
The city, Sokovia. Did we save it?
-班纳  听我说  -怎么了
- Banner, listen. - What?
索科威亚  奥创  那是两年前了
Sokovia. Ultron. That was two years ago.
你什么意思
What are you saying?
什么
What?
我做了两年绿巨人吗
I've been Hulk for two years?
恐怕是的
I'm afraid so.
发生了什么事啊
What the hell happened?
班纳  你需要知道一件事
Banner, there's something you should know.
需要语音启动
Voice activation required.
班纳
Banner.
欢迎  最强大的复仇者
Welcome, strongest Avenger.
-什么  -飞行日志
- What? - Ship's log.
托尔  我们在哪
Thor, where are we?
嗯  关于那个
Yeah, about that.
萨卡  请注意  我有坏消息
Sakaar, hear ye. Attention please. I have some bad news.
我最爱的尊贵冠军失踪了
My beloved exalted champion has turned up missing.
上街去为我的冠军欢庆吧
Take to the streets. Celebrate my champion.
那是谁
Who's that?
他算是这里的统治者
He kind of runs the place.
你在他家住了好一阵
You actually lived at his house for awhile.
-是吗  -是啊
- I did? - Yeah.
发生了好多事  我们俩最近打了一架
Quite a lot's happened. You and I had a fight recently.
-我赢了吗  -没有  我赢了  很轻松
- Did I win? - No, I won. Easily.
感觉不对呢
Doesn't sound right.
就是如此
Well, it's true.
看来那个诱拐犯
It seems that that criminally seductive
雷王把他偷走了
Lord of Thunder has stolen him away.
是诱拐犯雷神  我们得走了
Seductive God of Thunder. We need to move.
糟糕
Oh, no.
这太糟了
This is bad.
这太糟糕了
This is really, really bad.
托尔  我在抓狂
Thor, I think I'm freaking out.
别别
No, no, no.
别抓狂  你没事的  穿上这个
Don't freak out. You're okay. Put these on.
这是托尼的衣服
These are Tony's clothes.
-我知道  穿吧  -他也在吗
- I know, come on. - Is he here?
不  他没在  听着  保持冷静
No, he's not here. But listen. Just stay calm, okay?
太阳快下山了
The sun's going down.
太阳要下山了  太阳快下山了
The sun's getting really low. Sun's going down.
我很生气
I'm upset!
我非常生气
I'm very upset.
知道我喜欢生气的哪一点吗  怪罪
You know what I like about being upset? The blame.
现在  我就想做这个
Right now, that's the mindset that I'm in.
知道我怪谁吗
And you know who I'm blaming?
宗师  我可以...
Grandmaster, I can...
别打断我
Don't interrupt me!
给你
Here you go.
你干吗把融化棍递给我
Why are you handing me the melt stick?
他打断了我
He was interrupting.
那又不是死罪
That's not a capital violation.
我说到哪了
Where was I?
我的宝贝冠军不见了
My precious champion has come up missing,
这都是因为那个雷王
and it's all because of that Lord of Thunder.
都怪他
It's all because of him.
你哥哥
Your brother.
不管你们怎么回事  是领养还是另有隐情
Whatever the story is. Adopted, or complicated, or you know.
我相信有很多渊源
I'm sure there's a big history.
他是你带来的参赛者
And your contender...
亲爱的朋友
My dear friend,
如果你能给我12小时
if you were to give me 12 hours,
我可以把他俩都活着带回来
I could bring them both back to you. Alive.
我两小时就能做到
I could do it in two.
我一小时就能做到
I could do it in one.
打住吧
Let's stop there.
知道吗  我今早醒来时
You know what? I woke up this morning
想的是公开处决
thinking about a public execution.
但现在  我可以安于
But for now, I'll settle for this sweet little
"谁能先抓到他"
"Who's gonna get him first?"
所以  你们得抓紧了
So, you're on the clock.
你做了什么
What have you done?
我不听命于你  狗腿子
I don't answer to you, lackey.
是洛基
It's Loki.
你要听命于宗师
And you will answer to the Grandmaster.
你为什么要帮我哥哥和那个绿傻瓜逃跑
Why would you help my brother escape with that green fool?
我不帮任何人
I don't help anyone.
你是个女武神
You're a Valkyrie.
我以为女武神都惨死了
I thought the Valkyrie had all died gruesome deaths.
接下来要说什么想好了
Choose your next words wisely.
非常抱歉  那记忆一定很痛苦
I'm terribly sorry. Must be a very painful memory.
太阳快下山了  要下山了
The sun's going down. It's getting really low.
The sun's going down. It's getting real low.
该死
Oh, shoot.
-太阳快下山了  -你能不能别念叨了
- Sun's getting low. - Would you stop saying that?
我就是需要你保持冷静
I just need you to stay calm.
冷静  我在外星球上
Calm? I'm on an alien planet!
反正就是个星球  星球你也是去过的
This is just a planet. You've been on a planet before.
是啊  就一个
Yeah. One.
现在你去过俩了  这是好事
Now you've been on two. That's a good thing.
-这是新体验  -天呐
- It's a new experience. - Oh, my God.
我的神经元
My neurons,
已经在超过我大脑信息处理速度地运作了
they're firing faster than my brain can handle the information.
这次的感觉完全不一样
The whole thing is totally different this time.
以前  我一直觉得
In the past, I always felt
我和绿巨人各有一只手把着方向盘
like Hulk and I each had a hand on the wheel.
但这次  就好像他拿了车钥匙
But this time, it's like he had the keys to the car
而我被锁在后备箱里
and I was locked in the trunk.
你现在回来了  这才最重要
All right, well, you're back now. That's all that matters.
不  不是的
No, it's not what matters.
我就是想告诉你
What I'm trying to tell you,
如果我再变成绿巨人
is that if I turn into the Hulk again,
班纳可能就再也回不来了
Banner may never come back.
而且我们还困在一颗一切都让我紧张的星球上
And we're stranded on a planet that is designed to stress me out.
我们没被困  我会想到办法回家的
We're not stranded. I'm gonna figure out a way to get us home.
谢谢
Thank you.
不是你家  我的家  阿斯加德
Not your home, though. Asgard. My home.
什么
What?
听着  我的人民身陷危险
Listen, my people are in great danger.
你和我  我们得去击退一个非常厉害的人
You and I, we have to fight this really powerful being,
碰巧她还是我姐姐
who also happens to be my sister.
好吧  这太离谱了
Okay, that is so wrong on so many...
我不想打你姐姐  这是家庭问题
I don't wanna fight your sister. That's a family issue.
不  她是邪恶化身
No, she's an evil being.
我不管她怎么样
I don't care what she is.
我不要再打谁了  我受够了
I'm not fighting any more beings. I'm sick of it.
-什么  -我刚跟你说了
- What? - I just told you.
如果我再变成绿巨人  我会变不回来的
If I turn into the Hulk, I am never gonna come back again.
你都不在乎
And you don't care.
不不  我要组建一支队伍
No, no. I'm putting together the team.
绿巨人是火
The Hulk is the fire.
等等  你是在利用我得到绿巨人
Wait, you're just using me to get to the Hulk.
-什么  -真过分
- What? - It's gross.
什么  不是的
What? No!
你才不在乎我呢  你不是我的朋友
You don't care about me. You're not my friend.
才不是  我都不喜欢绿巨人  他就...
No! I don't even like the Hulk. He's all like...
"砸扁  砸扁  砸扁"
"Smash, smash, smash."
我更喜欢你
I prefer you.
谢谢
Thanks.
但老实说  在对抗邪恶化身这件事上
But if I'm being honest, when it comes to fighting evil beings,
他是很强大很有帮助
he is very powerful and useful.
班纳也很强大很有帮助
Yeah, Banner's powerful and useful, too.
是吗
Is he though?
好吧  绿巨人有几个博士学位  零
Okay. How many PhDs does Hulk have? Zero.
班纳有多少个博士学位  七个
How many PhDs does Banner have? Seven.
好吧  你不用打任何人
Fine, you don't have to fight anyone.
但我们在这里有危险  我们得走了
But we're in danger here, so we have to move.
你拿那个做什么
What are you doing with that?
我需要伪装  我是逃犯
I need a disguise. I'm a fugitive.
-我也需要伪装  -你就是伪装
- I need a disguise. - You are the disguise.
-我装成托尼·斯塔克  -什么
- I'll be Tony Stark. - What?
嗯  托尼和吉普赛人
Yeah. Tony and the gypsy.
不  你不是托尼  你是布鲁斯·班纳
No, no, you're not Tony. You're Bruce. Bruce Banner.
那你为什么把我打扮成托尼
Then why did you dress me up like Tony?
因为你光着呢
Because you were naked.
好吧  这是个好理由
Okay, I'll give you that.
你干什么呢  别乱抓了
What are you doing? Stop doing that!
托尼的裤子好紧
Tony wears his pants super tight.
-别抓了  -抱歉
- Stop it! - I'm sorry.
-你为什么怪怪的  -我不知道
- Why are you being so weird? - I don't know.
或许我在一个怪物体内
Maybe the fact that I was trapped for two years
困了两年所以才怪怪的
inside of a monster made me a little weird.
没事的
It's okay.
你没事的  冷静下来  走吧
You're good. Calm down. Calm down. Come on.
我们去阿斯加德
Listen, we're gonna go to Asgard
你再也不用去想绿巨人了
and you're not gonna have to think about the Hulk ever again.
-好吗  -好
- All right? - All right.
绿巨人  绿巨人
Hulk! Hulk! Hulk!
这可太糟了
This is bad.
班纳  班纳
Banner! Banner!
班纳
Banner!
托尔
Thor!
我正打算那么做呢
I was gonna do that.
我先做了
Yeah, well, I did it first.
很好  你在这儿干什么
That's good. What are you doing here?
你在这儿干什么  你不是要走吗
What are you doing here? I thought you were leaving.
出了点小岔子
I got sidetracked.
这是怎么...
What's with the...
是我的伪装
It's my disguise.
但我能看到你的脸
But I can see your face.
我这样你不就看不到了
Not when I do this, you can't.
你发型不错
Your hair looks nice.
我喜欢你的处理  换过吗  还是洗了
I like what you did with it. Change it? Washed it maybe?
她眼睛上那个是什么
What are those things on her eyes?
是她杀过的人吗
Are those people that she's killed?
她好美  强壮又勇敢
She's so beautiful and strong and courageous.
这家伙是谁
Who is this guy?
-我吗  -我朋友
- Who? Me? - He's a friend.
-我是布鲁斯  -我觉得我认识你
- I'm Bruce. - I feel like I know you.
我也这么觉得
I feel like I know you, too.
听着  我多年来浑浑噩噩  想忘记过去
Look, I've spent years in a haze, trying to forget my past.
萨卡似乎是借酒消愁  忘记过去
Sakaar seemed like the best place to drink and forget,
混吃等死的绝佳之处
and to die one day.
我是觉得你喝得太多了
I was thinking that you drink too much,
可能会因此没命
and that probably was gonna kill you.
我没打算停止喝酒
I don't plan to stop drinking.
但我不想忘记
But I don't wanna forget.
我不能再扭头不管了
I can't turn away anymore,
所以  如果我要死
so if I'm gonna die, well,
那不如是为了把我的剑
it may as well be driving my sword
插进那个屠夫婆娘的心脏
through the heart of that murderous hag.
-很好  -嗯
- Good. - Yeah.
所以  我是说  我想加入你的团队
So, I'm saying that I wanna be on the team.
有名字了吗
Has it got a name?
嗯  叫报仇者联盟
Yeah, it's called the Revengers.
报仇者
Revengers?
因为我要报仇  你也要报仇
Because I'm getting revenge. You're getting revenge.
还有你  你想报仇吗
You, too. What do you... Do you want revenge?
-我还没决定  -好
- I'm undecided. - Okay.
另外  我还带了示和礼物
Also, I've got a peace offering.
惊不惊喜
Surprise.
得确认一下
Just had to be sure.
你好  布鲁斯
Hello, Bruce.
上次我见你时  你想杀了所有人
So, last time I saw you, you were trying to kill everybody.
你现在都在忙什么
Where are you at these days?
每时每刻都不一样
It varies from moment to moment.
那是龙牙剑吗
Is that a Dragonfang?
是的
It is.
天啊
My God.
这就是著名的女武神之剑
This is the famed sword of the Valkyrie.
萨卡和阿斯加德
So, Sakaar and Asgard are about
之间离得不能更远了
as far apart as any two known systems.
最好的办法  是走城外的一个虫洞
Our best bet is a wormhole just outside of city limits.
在山达尔补充燃料  18个月后就能回到阿斯加德了
Refuel on Xandar, and we can be back in Asgard in 18 months.
不行  我们要走大的那个
Nope. We are going through the big one.
魔鬼屁眼
The Devil's Anus?
屁眼
Anus?
等等  谁的屁眼
Wait, wait, wait. Whose anus?
声明一下  我选的时候不知道它叫这么个名字
For the record, I didn't know it was called that when I picked it.
看起来像是在爱因斯坦罗森桥[虫洞]内
That looks like a collapsing neutron star inside of
坍缩的中子星
an Einstein-Rosen Bridge.
我们需要另找艘船  它会把我的船撕成碎片
We need another ship. That will tear mine to pieces.
她说得对  我们需要一艘能禁得住
She's right. We need one that can withstand
奇点短程线拉力的船
the geodetic strain from the singularity.
还得有脱机动力转向系统
And has an offline power steering system
没有机载电脑也能运行
that could also function without the on board computer.
还得有杯托
And we need one with cup holders,
因为我们要死了  喝酒吧
because we're gonna die. So, drinks!
我认识你吗  我好像认识你
Do I know you? I feel like I know you.
我也觉得我认识你  好奇怪
I feel like I know you, too. It's weird.
你觉得怎么样
What do you say?
穿过不稳定的宇宙传送门进行未知总星系旅行
Uncharted metagalactic travel through a volatile cosmic gateway.
这才叫冒险
Talk about an adventure.
-我们需要一艘飞船  -没错
- We need a ship. - Need a ship.
有那么一两艘飞船  绝对是最顶尖的
There are one or two ships. Absolute top of the line models...
你们不非得听我的
I don't mean to impose...
但宗师有很多飞船
But the Grandmaster has a great many ships.
我可能还偷到了他安全系统的密码
I may even have stolen the access codes to his security system.
还突然难以抑制地想行正义之举吗
And suddenly you're overcome with an urge to do the right thing.
天啊  不是
Heavens, no.
宗师对我的好感已消磨殆尽
I've run out of favor with the Grandmaster,
我用飞船和密码
and in exchange for codes and access to a ship,
换安全穿过屁眼
I'm asking for safe passage through the Anus.
你是说  你能让我们进入机库
You're telling us that you can get us access into the garage
而不触发警报
without setting off any alarms?
对  哥哥  我可以
Yes, brother. I can.
好  我先...提醒你们一下
Okay, can I just... A quick FYI.
我几分钟前跟他说话的时候
I was just talking to him just a couple minutes ago
他很想杀了我们
and he was totally ready to kill any of us.
他确实想杀我来着
He did try to kill me.
是啊  我也是  好多次呢
Yes, me too. On many, many occasions.
我们小时候  有一次
There was one time when we were children,
他变成了一条蛇
he transformed himself into a snake,
他知道我喜欢蛇
and he knows that I love snakes.
我捡起蛇  好好欣赏
So, I went to pick up the snake to admire it,
结果他变了回去
and he transformed back into himself
大喊  "嘿  是我"
and he was like, "Yeah, it's me!"
然后捅了我  我们当时才八岁
And he stabbed me. We were eight at the time.
我们要偷飞船的话
If we're boosting a ship
得把王宫的守卫引开
we're gonna need to draw some guards away from the palace.
放出野兽吧
Why not set the beast loose?
闭嘴
Shut up.
你们有野兽
You guys have a beast?
没有  没什么野兽  他在胡说
No, there's no beast. He's just being stupid.
我们要挑起革命
We're going to start a revolution.
-革命  -我过会儿再解释
- Revolution? - I'll explain later.
-他是谁来着 -过会儿再解释
- Who's this guy again? - I'll explain later.
你拉出来的
Is that some sort of protoplasm,
是原生质吗  还是卵
all the stuff that's coming out of you, or are they eggs?
看起来像卵
Looks like eggs.
我找寇格
I'm looking for Korg.
谁找我
Who's asking?
我知道是你
I know you're asking.
还有别人吗  还是只有你
Is there anyone else asking, or is it just you?
雷王向你问好
The Lord of Thunder sends his best.
革命开始了
The revolution has begun.
革命  怎么会这样
Revolution? How did this happen?
不知道
Don't know.
但角斗场的服从圆盘主机
But the arena's mainframe for the Obedience Disks
被关掉了
have been deactivated
奴隶都武装起来了
and the slaves have armed themselves.
我不喜欢那个词
I don't like that word.
哪个  主机吗
Which? Mainframe?
不是  我怎么会不喜欢"主机"
No. Why would I not like "mainframe"?
S开头的那个
No, the "S" word.
抱歉  在职囚犯们都武装起来了
Sorry, the prisoners with jobs have armed themselves.
这样好多了
Okay, that's better. That's better.
听着  我们应该谈谈
So, listen. We should talk.
我不同意
I disagree.
我们家从来就不擅长开诚布公
Open communication was never our family's forte.
可不是呢
You have no idea.
我们上次谈过后发现的真相很是了不得
Been quite the revelation since we last spoke.
你们好
Hello.
奥丁让我们聚在一起
Odin brought us together.
他的死让我们分裂  还挺诗意
It's almost poetic that his death should split us apart.
我们现在与陌生人无异
We might as well be strangers now.
两位王子  各自漂泊
Two sons of the crown, set adrift.
你不是不想谈吗
Thought you didn't wanna talk about it.
问题是...
Here's the thing.
我可能留在萨卡更好
I'm probably better off staying here on Sakaar.
我也这么想
That's exactly what I was thinking.
你刚刚是在同意我说的话吗
Did you just agree with me?
这地方太适合你了
Come on, this place is perfect for you.
野蛮  混乱  无法无天
It's savage, chaotic, lawless...
弟弟  你会在这儿如鱼得水的
Brother, you're gonna do great here.
你就真这么瞧不起我
Do you truly think so little of me?
洛基  我曾非常看重你
Loki, I thought the world of you.
我以为我们能永远并肩战斗
I thought we were gonna fight side by side forever.
但最终  你是你  我是我
But at the end of the day, you're you and I'm me.
我也说不好  或许你还有一丝良心  但
I don't know, maybe there's still good in you, but...
说实话  我们早已分道扬镳
let's be honest, our paths diverged a long time ago.
是啊
Yeah.
或许我们还是再也不要见面了比较好
It's probably for the best that we never see each other again.
这不是你一直想要的吗
It's what you always wanted.
我们来演"喊救命"吧
Hey, let's do "Get Help."
-什么  -"喊救命"
- What? - "Get Help."
不
No.
-来嘛  你最喜欢了  -我非常讨厌
- Come on, you love it. - I hate it.
-这招多棒啊  每次都好使  -太丢人了
- It's great. It works every time. - It's humiliating.
-你有更好的计划吗  -没有
- Do you have a better plan? - No.
那就这么办
We're doing it.
我才不要演"喊救命"
We are not doing "Get Help."
救命  求你们了
Get help! Please!
我弟弟快死了
My brother, he's dying.
救命  帮帮他吧
Get help! Help him!
经典
Classic.
我还是讨厌
Still hate it.
-太丢人了  -我又不丢人
- It's humiliating. - Not for me, it's not.
好了  她让我们上哪艘船来着
Now, which one's the ship she told us to get?
司令号
The Commodore.
好的
Right.
不过我觉得应该也没什么用
Though I feel it won't make much of a difference.
洛基
Loki.
我知道我背叛过你很多次
I know I've betrayed you many times before,
但这次真不是针对你
but this time it's truly nothing personal.
抓到你的赏金会让我过得很阔绰
The reward for your capture will set me up nicely.
你果然从不是个重感情的人
Never one for sentiment, were you?
无情会过得更轻松些
Easier to let it burn.
我同意
I agree.
看起来好痛
That looks painful.
亲爱的弟弟  你越来越好猜了
Dear brother, you're becoming predictable.
我信任你  你背叛我
I trust you, you betray me.
一遍又一遍
Round and round in circles we go.
洛基  人生  是要成长的
See, Loki, life is about... It's about growth.
是要改变的
It's about change.
但你好像只想保持原样
But you seem to just wanna stay the same.
我想说的是
I guess what I'm trying to say
你永远都只是恶作剧之神
is that you'll always be the God of Mischief,
但你本可不止如此
but you could be more.
我就把这个留给你了
I'll just put this over here for you.
好了  我们都还有地方要去  所以祝你好运了
Anyway, all got places to be, so good luck, I guess.
好了  你能搞定的
All right, you can figure this out.
不过是又一艘宇宙飞船罢了
It's just another spaceship.
忠诚的萨卡人
Loyal Sakaarians,
雷王偷了我的飞船和我最爱的冠军
Lord of Thunder has stolen my ship and my favorite champion.
萨卡人  升空  把他打下来
Sakaarians, take to the skies. Bring him down.
不要让他离开这个星球
Do not let him leave this planet.
-打得不错  -谢谢
- Good shot! - Thanks.
开门
Open the doors.
好
Okay.
我希望你比看起来要坚强一些
I hope that you're tougher than you look.
为什么
Why?
我们不该反击什么的吗
Shouldn't we be shooting back or something?
是应该
Yes, we should.
这船上的武器在哪里
Where are the guns on this ship?
没有武器
There aren't any.
-这是艘消遣船  -什么
- It's a leisure vessel. - What?
宗师用它来享乐的  群交派对之类的
Grandmaster uses it for his good times, orgies and stuff.
她刚刚是说宗师用这船办群交派对吗
Did she just say the Grandmaster uses it for orgies?
是的
Yeah.
什么都别碰
Don't touch anything.
不  不
No! No!
-不  -不
- No! - No!
进来
Get inside!
马上
In a minute.
我该去帮帮她  你过来开
I should probably go and help. Here, take the wheel.
不行  我不会开这个
No. I don't know how to fly one of these.
你是个科学家  用你的博士学位去搞明白
You're a scientist. Use one of your PhDs.
那些学位都不是外星飞船驾驶啊
None of them are for flying alien spaceships!
好吧  拜托
Okay, come on.
这上面肯定有枪的
There's gotta be a gun on this thing.
那看起来好像是枪
That looks like a gun.
今天我生日  今天我生日
It's my birthday. It's my birthday.
今天我生日
It's my birthday.
好啊
Yeah!
伙计们  我们马上就要进入恶魔屁眼了
Guys, we're coming up on the Devil's Anus!
在那儿
There she is.
我们逃离的途径
Our ticket out of here.
这是什么
Hey, what's this?
谢谢
Thank you.
老兄  我们要跳上那艘超大飞船离开这里
Hey, man. We're about to jump on that ginormous spaceship.
要一起来吗
You wanna come?
你们看起来确实急需一位领袖
You do seem like you're in desperate need of leadership.
谢谢
Why, thank you.
来了
Here we go.
该死
Shit.
阿斯加德人民
Asgardians...
有不知好歹的人
Some misguided soul
偷走了彩虹桥之剑
has stolen the Bifrost sword.
告诉我们它在哪里
Tell us where it is
否则后果自负
or there will be consequences.
严重的后果
Bad ones.
有人说吗
Well?
你
You.
不  住手
No! Stop!
求你们
Please.
动手啊  处刑人
Well? Executioner?
等等
Wait!
我知道剑在哪
I know where the sword is.
没想到我还能再回来
I never thought I'd be back here.
我以为会更美一些呢
I thought it'd be a lot nicer.
倒不是说它不美  只是着火了
I mean, not that it's not nice. It's just, it's on fire.
看  山上
Here, up here in the mountains.
有热信号  那里聚集了很多人
Heat signatures. People clustered together.
她要去找他们了
She's coming for them.
好  把我丢在王宫  我去引开她
Okay, drop me off at the palace and I'll draw her away.
你想害死自己吗
And get yourself killed?
困在那里的人才是最重要的
The people trapped down there are all that matters.
我去应付海拉时
While I'm dealing with Hela,
你们得疏散阿斯加德的人民
I need you two to help get everyone off Asgard.
我们要怎么做啊
How the hell are we supposed to do that?
我在地面上有人接应
I have a man on the ground.
阿斯加德人民
Asgard.
她来了
She's here.
这下飞船有火力了
Now the ship has a gun.
交给我吧
I'll take it from here.
我在武器库发现了这个
I found this in the armory.
祝你好运
Good luck.
陛下
Your Majesty...
别死了
Don't die.
你懂我意思的
You know what I mean.
别停步
We must keep moving!
去彩虹桥
Go to the Bifrost!
姐姐
Sister.
你还活着
You're still alive.
我喜欢你对这里的改造  重装修了啊
I love what you've done with the place. Redecorating, I see.
看来我们父亲解决
It seems our father's solution
所有问题的思路都是掩盖
to every problem was to cover it up.
或驱逐
Or to cast it out.
他对你说你有资格  他也对我说过这话
He told you you were worthy. He said the same thing to me.
你瞧
You see?
你根本不了解他
You never knew him.
没见过他最辉煌的时刻
Not at his best.
奥丁和我曾让整个文明淹死在血泪之中
Odin and I drowned entire civilizations in blood and tears.
你以为这些金子是哪来的
Where do you think all this gold came from?
然后  有一天
And then, one day,
他突然决定做个仁慈的君王
he decided to become a benevolent king.
制造和平  保护生命
To foster peace, to protect life.
生下你
To have you.
我能理解你的愤怒
I understand why you're angry.
你毕竟是我姐姐
And you are my sister,
严格讲  有权继承王位
and technically have a claim to the throne.
相信我  我也愿意别人来统治
And believe me, I would love for someone else to rule.
但那不能是你
But it can't be you.
你真是坏透了
You're just the worst.
好吧  起来
Okay, get up.
你坐在我的位置上了
You're in my seat.
父亲曾对我说
You know, Father once told me
一位明君从不挑起战争
that a wise king never seeks out war.
但必须时刻做好准备
But must always be ready for it.
回去
Go back!
Go!
老实说  我以为你有更大本事呢
To be honest, I expected more.
海姆达尔
Heimdall!
剑
The sword!
我们的不同之处在于
Here's the difference between us.
我是奥丁的长女
I'm Odin's firstborn,
合法继承人  阿斯加德的拯救者
the rightful heir, the savior of Asgard.
你什么都不是
And you're nothing.
如此简单  瞎子都看得清
So simple, even a blind man could see it.
这下你让我想起了爸爸
Now you remind me of Dad.
那只臭狗打不死
The stupid dog won't die!
没事了  交给我吧
Everything's gonna be all right now. I got this.
你想知道我是谁
You wanted to know who I am?
你说什么呢
What the hell are you talking about?
你会看到的
You'll see!
瞧  谁都别想跑
You see? No one's going anywhere.
我会拿到那把剑
I'll get that sword,
哪怕我为此要杀光他们每个人
even if I have to kill every single one of them to do it.
伙计
Hey, man.
我是寇格  这是米克
I'm Korg. This is Miek.
我们要跳上那艘飞船离开这里
We're gonna jump on that spaceship and get out of here.
要一起来吗
Wanna come?
你们的拯救者到了
Your savior is here.
想我了吗
Did you miss me?
大家快上船吧
Everyone, on that ship now.
欢迎回家  我看到你来了
Welcome home. I saw you coming.
当然了
Of course you did.
虽然是英勇之举  但你们毫无胜算
It's a valiant effort, but you never stood a chance.
瞧
You see...
我不是女王  或怪物
I'm not a queen or a monster.
我是死亡女神
I'm the Goddess of Death.
你是什么的神来着
What were you the god of, again?
就算是你有两只眼睛时
Even when you had two eyes,
也只能看清一半
you'd see only half the picture.
她太强大了  没有锤子  我做不到
She's too strong. Without my hammer, I can't.
你是托尔  锤子之神吗
Are you Thor, the God of Hammers?
锤子是用来帮你控制力量  集中力量的
That hammer was to help you control your power, to focus it.
不是你力量的源泉
It was never your source of strength.
太迟了  她已经夺下了阿斯加德
It's too late. She's already taken Asgard.
阿斯加德不是一个地方  从来不是
Asgard is not a place. Never was.
这里就可以是阿斯加德
This could be Asgard.
阿斯加德是我们人民的所在
Asgard is where our people stand.
而现在  那些人民需要你的帮助
Even now, right now, those people need your help.
我不像你那么强大
I'm not as strong as you.
是啊
No...
你比我更强大
You're stronger.
告诉我  弟弟
Tell me, brother.
你是什么的神来着
What were you the god of, again?
-你来迟了  -你缺了只眼睛
- You're late. - You're missing an eye.
还没打完呢
This isn't over.
我觉得我们该解散报仇者
I think we should disband the Revengers.
用闪电打她
Hit her with a lightning blast.
我刚用史上
I just hit her with the
最大的闪电打她了
biggest lightning blast in the history of lightning.
毫无作用
It did nothing.
我们得抵住她  直到大家都上了船
We just need to hold her off until everyone's on board.
那也不是个完
It won't end there.
海拉在阿斯加德待得越久  她就越强大
The longer Hela's on Asgard, the more powerful she grows.
她会找到我们的
She'll hunt us down.
我们得在此时此地阻止她
We need to stop her here and now.
我们怎么办
So what do we do?
我不要再演"喊救命"了
I'm not doing "Get Help."
阿斯加德不是一个地方  是人民所在
Asgard's not a place, it's a people.
洛基
Loki,
我们根本不是要阻止诸神黄昏
this was never about stopping Ragnarok.
我们要引发诸神黄昏
This was about causing Ragnarok.
苏尔特尔的王冠  在地堡里
Surtur's crown, the vault.
只能如此
It's the only way.
真大胆  哥哥
Bold move, brother.
我都不敢想
Even for me.
我们来吧
Shall we?
你先请
After you.
这真是疯了
This is madness.
走  快走
Go! Go, now!
为了阿斯加德
For Asgard.
海拉
Hela!
永恒烈火将让你重生
With the Eternal Flame, you are reborn.
海拉  够了
Hela, enough!
你想要阿斯加德  它是你的了
You want Asgard, it's yours.
不管你在玩什么把戏  不会成功的
Whatever game you're playing, it won't work.
你休想打败我
You can't defeat me.
我知道
No, I know.
但他能
But he can.
不
No.
在我脚下震颤吧  阿斯加德
Tremble before me, Asgard!
我是你的末日
I am your reckoning!
人民安全了
The people are safe.
那才是最重要的
That's all that matters.
我们实现了预言
We're fulfilling the prophecy.
我恨这则预言
I hate this prophecy.
我也是  但我们没别的办法
So do I, but we have no choice.
苏尔特尔毁掉阿斯加德
Surtur destroys Asgard,
才能毁掉海拉  我们的人民才能生还
he destroys Hela, so that our people may live.
但我们得让他做完  否则
But we need to let him finish the job, otherwise...
不
No!
绿巨人  停下  你个白痴
Hulk, stop, you moron!
绿巨人  停下
Hulk, stop.
就这一次  别砸了
Just for once in your life, don't smash.
大怪物
Big monster!
我们走吧
Let's go!
好吧
Fine.
我是阿斯加德的末日
I am Asgard's doom!
毁得还不算太严重
The damage is not too bad.
只要地基还撑得住
As long as the foundations are still strong,
我们还能重建
we can rebuild this place.
它可以成为全宇宙人民
It will become a haven for all peoples
和外星人的避难所
and aliens of the universe.
这下地基是没了  抱歉
Now those foundations are gone. Sorry.
我做了什么啊
What have I done?
你让我们免遭灭绝
You saved us from extinction.
阿斯加德不是一个地方
Asgard is not a place...
是人民的所在
It's a people.
挺适合你
It suits you.
或许你也没那么坏  弟弟
Maybe you're not so bad after all, brother.
或许吧
Maybe not.
谢谢
Thank you.
如果你真在这里  我或许还会抱抱你
If you were here, I might even give you a hug.
我在这儿
I'm here.
你的王位
Your throne.
那么  阿斯加德国王
So, King of Asgard.
我们去哪
Where to?
我不确定
I'm not sure.
有什么提议吗
Any suggestions?
米克  你是哪来的
Miek, where are you from?
米克死了
Miek's dead.
是啊  我刚刚在桥上不小心踩到了他
Yeah, no, I accidentally stomped on him on the bridge.
我好愧疚  我抱了他一天了
I've just felt so guilty, I've been carrying him around all day.
米克  你还活着
Miek, you're alive!
他还活着  你刚问什么来着  哥们
He's alive, guys. What was your question again, bro?
去地球吧
Earth it is.
雷神3：诸神黄昏
你真觉得回地球是个好主意吗
Do you really think it's a good idea to go back to Earth?
当然  地球人民喜欢我  我很受欢迎
Yes, of course. The people of Earth love me. I'm very popular.
我换个说法
Let me rephrase that.
你真觉得带我回地球是个好主意吗
Do you really think it's a good idea to bring me back to Earth?
老实说  或许不是
Probably not, to be honest.
别担心  弟弟
I wouldn't worry, brother.
我觉得一切都会没问题的
I feel like everything's gonna work out fine.
天呐
Oh, boy.
我想说  我为你们所有人骄傲
I just gotta say, I'm proud of you all.
这场革命非常成功  大家好棒
This revolution has been a huge success. Yay, us!
鼓励鼓励自己  干得好
Pat on the back. Pat on the back.
来嘛  不吗
Come on. No?
我也是  因为我是其中重要的一部分
Me too. 'Cause I've been a big part of it.
没有人去推翻  哪里来的革命呢
Can't have a revolution without somebody to overthrow.
所以  不客气
So, you're welcome.
我们平手了
And it's a tie.
雷神将在《复仇者联盟3: 无限战争》中回归